Christian Bartram

Senior Software Engineer

A collaborative and diligent University of North Florida Information Systems Major with four years of software development experience in the financial and healthcare industries. Well versed in object oriented programming languages and frameworks such as Java, CI/CD, GraphQL, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, React, Node.JS, Python, Spark, Kafka, Agile Development, Git, and REST



cbartram3@gmail.com

407-247-0519

McClean Virginia

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer Capital One

02/2018 - Present

McClean Virginia

Capital One is a bank holding company specializing in credit cards, auto loans, banking and savings products

• Built an enterprise machine learning platform written in Java on the Spring framework. Leveraged tech like GraphQL, Kubernetes, S3, EC2 and DynamoDB to build and scale a durable & resilient full stack app. Slashed costs and transitioned a legacy monitoring application to the cloud using a dev-ops first architecture and serverless design. Created a fully automated Jenkins pipeline for instantly deploying infrastructure & code to AWS.

Contact: Lance Creath - lance.creath@capitalone.com

Software Engineer Intern Florida Blue Cross Blue Shield

03/2017 - 12/2017

Jacksonville Florida

Nationwide Health Insurance provider

Achievements

• Rapidly developed prototype e-business applications in React, NodeJS and Java. Worked in an agile team to meet rigorous deadlines and yield production quality code. Streamlined development operations with version control, unit testing, continuous integration, and scheduled releases. Documented detailed system specifications while maintaining planned and unplanned internally developed applications.

Contact: James Smith - James.Smith@bcbsfl.com

Backend Software Engineer Intern Clearsense

01/2016 - 03/2017

Jacksonville Florida

Startup predictive data analytics firm in the healthcare industry

Achievements

 Wrote enterprise level production ready code in an agile software development team. Effectively wrote, tested, debugged, reviewed, and deployed code to business clients. Planned and executed major software releases. Assisted in developing a cloud infrastructure centered around Hadoop & Big Data processing to deliver both analytical and real time solutions to the healthcare industry.

Contact: Jimmy Hurff - jhurff@clearsense.com

EDUCATION

BS/Information Systems University of North Florida

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Github (07/2012 – Present) 🗹

 Please see my Github account for a full list of personal projects and accomplished works. https://github.com/cbartram

Ignite Code (01/2019 – Present)

Created a server-less web application to help teach full stack development to anyone! Ignite contains over 75 hours of high quality interactive full stack videos taught by me ranging from topics such as HTML, CSS and Javascript to Git, Agile, AWS, Testing, Security, Dev-ops and Databases.

Nanoleaf Layout (04/2017 – Present)

An NPM package which helps developers manage and control their Nanoleaf smart lighting system. This package is the only one of its kind and has over 2,500 downloads on NPM every month!

Volunteer Management Software (08/2016 – 04/2017)

Designed, developed, managed and deployed a Volunteer Management software solution to organize and record volunteer information, hours, donations and events.

ACHIEVEMENTS

AWS Solutions Architect Certified (05/2019 – Present)

Completed the Amazon Web Services Solutions Architect Associate certification demonstrating my proficiency in creating durable, elastic, and highly available cloud based applications.

UNF Computing Symposium 1st Place (11/2016 - 11/2016)

First UNF student in the schools history to achieve back to back 1st place awards for the Computing Symposium (Fall 2016, Spring 2017). This award is highly competitive and includes over fifty different software teams who compete for a monetary prize.